Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Publications RG.49
New York University Archives
NYU Abu Dhabi Publications
2008-2019
2011-2016
New York University Archives
New York University in Abu Dhabi
RG.49
4.5 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes, and one folder in a shared manuscript box.
New York University Abu Dhabi (NYUAD) is a degree-granting liberal arts and research university located in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates and is part of the NYU's Global Network University. NYUAD opened in a temporary location in 2008 before moving to its permanent home on Saadiyat Island, Abu Dhabi in 2010, the same year it accepted its first class of students. The campus offers 22 majors in liberal arts and sciences. Established in 2008 as a center of advanced research, scholarly, and creative activity in Abu Dhabi, The Institute assembles academics, professionals, and leaders from around the world to its academic conferences and public program to discuss research areas and topics of local and global significance. This collection consists of publications produced by NYUAD, and includes promotional and administration publications, such as course catalogs and graduating class yearbooks. Materials also include an book commemorating the inauguration of NYU Abu Dhabi Institute.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Accruals
Further accruals are expected.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by NYU Abu Dhabi in 2015 and June 2019. The accession numbers associated with these gift are 2016.005, 2019.066, and 2019.077.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical Note
New York University Abu Dhabi (NYUAD) is a degree-granting liberal arts and research university located in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates and is part of the NYU's Global Network University. NYUAD opened in a temporary location in 2008 before moving to its permanent home on Saadiyat Island, Abu Dhabi in 2010, the same year it accepted its first class of students. The campus offers 22 majors in liberal arts and sciences.
Established in 2008 as a center of advanced research, scholarly, and creative activity in Abu Dhabi, The Institute assembles academics, professionals, and leaders from around the world to its academic conferences and public program to discuss research areas and topics of local and global significance.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of publications produced by New York University Abu Dhabi (NYUAD). Materials include promotional and administration publications distributed by NYUAD, such as course catalogs and graduating class yearbooks. Materials also include a book commemorating the inauguration of NYU Abu Dhabi Institute and a 2013 internal concept document.
Universities and Colleges -- Alumni and alumnae.; School yearbooks.; Abū Ẓaby (United Arab Emirates); Booklets.
- NYU Abu Dhabi Institute -- Inaugural Commemorative Book, 2008 (Box 1, Box 6)
  Scope and Contents
  ID Number: 466. Description: 14 x 14 purple book. Creator/Donor/Subject: Abu Dhabi Institute.
- Class of 2014 Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Class of 2015 Publication (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Class of 2016 Publication (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Class of 2017 Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Year in Review Booklets, 2011-2014 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, 2015-2016 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, 2016-2017 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, 2017-2018 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, 2018-2019 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Promotional Material, 2011-2018 (Box 9)